Some secrets won't stay buried.
The Cat's Meow is a drama, mystery, thriller film directed by Peter Bogdanovich.
Semi-true story of the Hollywood murder that occurred at a star-studded
gathering aboard William Randolph Hearst's yacht in 1924.
Marion Davies, played by Kirsten Dunst.
W. R. Hearst, played by Edward Herrmann.
Charlie Chaplin, played by Eddie Izzard.
Thomas Ince, played by Cary Elwes.
Elinor Glyn, played by Joanna Lumley.
Louella Parsons, played by Jennifer Tilly.
The Cat's Meow is a 2001 historical drama film directed by Peter Bogdanovich, and starring Kirsten Dunst,
Eddie Izzard, Edward Herrmann, Cary Elwes, Joanna Lumley, Jennifer Tilly, and Ronan Vibert.
The screenplay by Steven Peros is based on his 1997 play of the same title,
which was inspired by the mysterious death of film mogul Thomas H.
Ince that occurred on William Randolph Hearst's yacht during a weekend
cruise celebrating Ince's birthday in November 1924.
Among those in attendance were Hearst's longtime companion and film actress Marion Davies, fellow actor
Charlie Chaplin, writer Elinor Glyn, columnist Louella Parsons, and actress Margaret Livingston.
The film provides a speculative assessment on the
unclear manner of Ince's death.
An international co-production between the United States, the United Kingdom, and Germany, The Cat's Meow
was primarily shot in Greece, which served as a stand-in for coastal Southern California.
The film premiered at the Locarno International Film Festival in 2001, and was
released theatrically in the United States by Lionsgate in April 2002.
It grossed $3.6 million worldwide, and received largely
favorable reviews from film critics.
The film explores themes of blackmail, kiss, love, murder, mistress.
The tone is intense and emotional and mind_bending.